# Birendra Kr. Sharma

Sr. Software Developer @ Marmeto

+91-9709857928 kumarbeeru.kbs@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/birendrakr kumarbeeru.github.io

## **Profile Summary**

A competent professional with 4+ years of experience in Software Development Life Cycle: Requirement Gathering, Bug Tracking, Debugging, Application Development, Unit Testing, Deployment, and Documentation. Have worked on several technologies: Node Js, Express Js, MySQL, MongoDB, React Js, Laravel, SQL, Rest API, Docker, OOPS, and Data Structures. I describe myself as – Innovating, Executing, Collaborating, and Having Fun! My strong points are my Responsibility and Punctuality.

#### **Skills**

**Node Js, React Js**, JavaScript, **REST API**, **GIT**, MySQL, **MongoDB**, Laravel, AWS, Data Structure, TypeScript, OOPs, Rest API, GraphQL, Jest, Supertest, Docker.

## **Work Experience**

#### Sr. Software Developer

Company: Marmeto, Url: marmeto.com, Bengaluru, Karnataka 11/2021 – Present

- Grooming and Motivating the team.
- Monitoring and maintaining the code quality and standards.
- Solving the clients' doubts.
- Designed architecture & developed Multiple Shopify Public App using NodeJS, Laravel, MongoDB, MySQL and React.
- Developed the Woo-commerce Plugin.
- Designed architecture & developed Shopify Payment Gateway using MERN stack.
- Maintaining the existing shopify apps and customs Solutions.
- Developed Many Shopify Custom solutions.

#### **Software Developer**

Company: Web Revolution, Url: webrevolution.in, Ahmadabad, Gujarat 2019 – 2021

- Modified Laravel, and Javascript Code to optimize the page performance for faster loading and browsing.
- Developed APIs of crypto wallet systems using Laravel and MySql and wrote swagger documentation for api testing as a back-end developer.
- Designed and developed the project using React.js(Redux), Laravel, and MySql.
- Designed and developed the admin panel of Shopify shop using Laravel and MySql.
- Updated the Mobile Application's feature and optimized the React Native(Redux) code to fulfill the client's requirements.
- Designed and developed the Telegram bots using laravel and python.

Developed the desktop application using python.

#### **Full-Stack Developer**

#### Freelance

2016 - 2019

- Understand the requirements of the client and fulfill them.
- Coordinated with the team and managed the complete life cycle of the project development.
- Developed many projects using Laravel, JS, Jquery, React Native, Expo, and MySql.

### **Education**

### **BCA (Bachelor in Computer Applications) - 2019**

→ T. N. B College Bhagalpur, Bihar

## Language

Hindi and English

## **Project Summary**

- 1. Shopify Payment App:
  - URL: <a href="https://apps.shopify.com/fastpay">https://apps.shopify.com/fastpay</a>
  - Language : MERN Stack With TypeScript
  - Role: Full Stack Developer
  - Responsibilities: Database Design, Frontend Development, Api Development
- 2. Easy Parcel Shopify Shipping App:
  - Url: <a href="https://apps.shopify.com/easyparcel-delivery-made-easy">https://apps.shopify.com/easyparcel-delivery-made-easy</a>
  - Language and Tools: Laravel, React and Mysql
  - Role : Full Stack Developer
  - Responsibilities: Database Design, Frontend Development and Api Development
- 3. Project Snapbots Wallet (Crypto Wallet)
  - Url: https://app.snapbots.io/#/pages/login
  - Language and Tools: Laravel, Angular, MySql, Swagger, Sentry
  - Role: Back-end Developer
  - Responsibilities: Designed the database and Developed the Apis.